welcome to another installment of the
right to ask him redux video series if
you haven't been following along it will
probably be much easier to start at the
beginning since each video builds on
where the previous video of staff and
remember to get up to speed on Redux
itself you really can't beat ya diode
videos
paradoxes creator Dan Abrams sonar last
video we stand upright and redux to use
the thunk middleware so that we can make
a seng calls ever use that to call our
JSON server with the get to grab a
couple of records and displayed on the
page we're going to build on that
example and now we're gonna start
posting to that same API and the great
thing about JSON server is it allows
that and it'll actually take the updates
and apply them to RDV don't chase on
file so that we can use this like a real
API everything is fine based so let's
take a look at that would open a new
terminal window into my new window we're
just gonna take a look at a quick post
using curl so no posts to localhost 3000
/ tasks with the content types at
applications like JSON and the data
sample their press ENTER there and get a
response
sample it has no idea of two but I go
back into my editor and take a look at
TV that JSON will see that has been
updated with that data so no clear that
out
and might add some code so that we can
post from our actual application so the
first thing to do is to create a new tag
and this tag is gonna hold the form is
going to add a new task so a new file
and I'm gonna call that test performed
at tank and in their file go ahead and
give it a true tags were gonna need some
form tags and its form is gonna have a
non submit handler that's going to point
to a function called handle submit
create a moment gonna take an input type
text with the name new task will give
the submit button and I'm gonna throw in
some script as with the handle submit
function and in my form handler I'm
gonna call this tied up start at TASC
asset value from input text field so add
task is going to be passed into the tag
as natural you are to do at tag and once
we have submitted the form we also want
to clear out the value that was in the
employee so we just had a call to this
date new task value and set it equal an
empty string so now I want to go into
actions done Jas so the end of our
actions digest file what a function call
dad task and will accept new task as an
argument and now that I have that
function gonna go up to the top of the
file and expose that through module .
exports now go back down to a function
and its going to reach her new function
with dispatching get state as its
arguments and in their function we're
gonna dispatcher toggle loading action
and then I'll show are looking into
catering case adding a task takes a long
time and we're gonna set up our exit XHR
request a request that open with post
our path to tasks call center request
header content type application / JSON
and we'll set up a function to handle
the onload and we want to send a request
and when we send a request we want to
pass it
Jason stratified value with our new task
passed in as the name property
so this will create a new task JSON
server automatically take care of the
idea of you and in the onload function
will take our response text will parse
that pass it into a variable called data
and a call to dispatch and we're going
to dispatch new task had it with the
idea and the name of the new task and
before I move on to create a new test a
detection creator let's add a second
call dispatch to hide are loading
indicator so-called dispatch struggling
with loss and then I'll Haider indicator
and before I forget we're gonna wrap our
data and dispatch call to news has got
it in its statement the checks for a
successful response so check if request
status is greater than 200 West Ham 410
will dispatch that new task added with
her data center Todd loading files can
be outside at Erica's wanna make sure we
hide loading indicator either way now
let's create that new test cabbage
action creator so we have functioned new
task at it and it's going to accept idea
name I'm going to return an object width
at a property called task added and a
property with an object with an idea and
an improperly says gonna represent our
new task and now that we have this setup
let's go back to a reducer and set up a
case for the task added action so I case
task added and we're gonna have that
returned object at a sign with our
existing state and an object where tasks
is replaced with the existing tasks plus
a caller can cat to take that new task
and tack it onto the end of the
resulting array so now to make sure that
our task form is included in the bundle
we're gonna add require call for our
task form tank and in order to do at
that tag file you need to add the markup
to show task for him and her task form
needs an event handler function if you
remember when we created task form we're
passing a call center handle submit
we're calling options
dot had task so we need to pass that in
so add tasks can equal expression and in
that expression we're gonna pass this .
handle new task we're gonna have a
handle new task function to our to-do
app tank it's been accepted HASC and
it's going to cost or dispatch and it's
going to dispatch al actions . a desk
and this keeps all of our redux store
specific functionality outside of our
tags for container manages that so it'll
handle calls to dispatch and updating
the state subscribe and now that we have
this setup let's go to our browser and
check it out and we'll see that the
leading indicator flashes for a brief
second it has this value back and my
state is updated when the response comes
back from JSON server thank you for
watching hope you found this video
helpful be sure to keep an eye out for
the next video in the series